If you want better SEO results and
better AI search visibility, you've got
to know how to do keyword research like
a pro. And in this video, I'm going to
show you four keyword research
techniques that will unlock so many
opportunities, you probably won't need
to run a full keyword research process
again for the next 6 to 12 months. My
name is Nathan Gotch and I've been doing
SEO since 2013 and I've led hundreds of
successful SEO and AI search campaigns.
So, let's walk through my keyword
research process from start to finish.
So, this is the exact template that we
use on every SEO campaign and this is
one we've been we've built many, many
years ago and we've continually just
refined and improved over time. And so,
it might look a little overwhelming at
first, but I can assure you once you
understand how this template works, it's
it's really something you're going to
want to swipe, something you're going to
take a lot of these these elements. So,
let me walk you through this real
quickly. So, a couple key things here is
this is really built for an agency
situation and you know, an agency that's
working with a client, but you could use
this for your own campaign. You would
just be the client, okay? So, let's say
Rankability was the client, all right?
That would's how it would work. So, that
is really kind of the container. Now, a
couple key things here. Uh priority is
very important, which is just measuring,
you know, what is going to be the
priority of these keywords and I'll show
you in step three how to actually
prioritize your keywords, okay? Source
is important. Where did you actually
find that keyword? So, I'm going to be
walking through many different
techniques where you can find keywords
here in a second. Cluster is also
critical. You want to put every single
keyword that you find into a bucket. You
want to have it in its appropriate
cluster because what that allows you to
do is see, okay, where do we have a a
lot of focus right now or where do we
have big gaps, okay? You can at a very
high level, you can see that right away
when you start to fill this in.
Obviously, the keyword or topic that
you're going to go after, SERP features
is very, very important to put in here
as well because this will ultimately
help you estimate what the organic CTR
is going to be, okay? But not only that,
as I'll show you here very soon,
you can also look at the SERPs as a a
way to determine what your strategy
should be as far as attacking different
elements in those SERPs, okay? So, then
we have search volume which goes without
saying. We have KD which is just
measuring how many links a particular
page has
uh in the top 10, and that's very
important because it ultimately
determine what our link budget is going
to have to be.
Cost per click, this one always confuses
a lot of people, but this is actually
very important for keyword selection.
So, uh cost per click doesn't matter for
SEO per se, but it matters for
determining keyword value. So, if you
see that a lot of advertisers are, you
know, advertising for a particular
keyword, that means it's likely very
valuable, okay? So, that's why this is
important. So, when we get to the
filtering process, you're going to
filter keywords that do have higher CPC
value cuz it means more than likely
they're they're more valuable than those
that do not, okay?
Current position, this is where you
currently rank for this particular
keyword, okay? So, there's kind of two
different keyword research approaches
you want to have. You have the one where
you're uh extracting your existing
keywords from the keywords you already
rank for in the top 100, and then
another part of the keyword research
process is just identifying completely
new keywords, those that your website
does not currently rank for, okay? So,
those are kind of the two different uh
routes that you can take, okay? Your
current URL, this is simply what URL is
actually ranking for this keyword in the
top 100.
Next thing which is absolutely critical
is intent, okay? So, I've I have some
rejects in here that automatically
filters this through, but basically what
happens as soon as you put a keyword in,
it will automatically categorize it as
informational or commercial intent. Now,
we've kept these categories
intentionally broad. There's obviously
many different subsets of search intent,
but just to keep it simple, we focus on
that. Okay? So, if you can just break it
down into informational, commercial,
you're going to be in pretty good shape.
Okay?
And then the opportunity. So, this is
just our own personal categorization,
but basically the way we look at it is
any keyword that's ranking between
positions 2 and 15 is what we define as
a low-hanging fruit. Okay? Then aside
from that, if it's from 16 to 50, we
just we just label that as an existing
keyword. Still very important, but just
goes in that existing bucket. Then any
keywords beyond position 50 is what we
call a clustering opportunity. Now, not
every keyword in that range will qualify
as a clustering opportunity, but the
reason why we say that is because a lot
of keywords that are underperforming,
you will often find that the page that's
currently ranking, let's say it's
ranking number 72, that page is either
not relevant enough, not good enough, or
some other reason why it's not ranking.
So, we really want to isolate that group
of keywords and say, "Okay, why why is
this page not performing very well for
this particular keyword?" Now, you could
technically have a perfect page for that
keyword, but it may be lacking internal
link coverage. It may be lacking uh
proper topic coverage around that core
topic. It could be lacking backlinks.
Okay? So, there's other variables, other
reasons why a a page could be
underperforming, but we do find a lot of
the time that there's sometimes an
intent mismatch. Okay? So, that's why
identifying that clustering opportunity,
which is any keywords beyond position
50. Okay? Those are what you would
identify. Okay?
So, you do that that gets automatically
categorized.
And then we'll keep going through here.
We'll skip through some of this. And
then the right side of this part is the
prioritization, which we'll be getting
into more, but basically the way this
template works is it automatically does
all of this. Okay? So, it's got to, you
you all these formulas in here. And as
soon as a keyword gets put in there,
this has its own kind of automatic
scoring mechanism so that you can get a
an end score here, a point total. So,
then you know, like, okay, based on all
these variables that we have, these are
likely some of the you know, this group
of keywords are the best ones to go
after based on
our current position of our website and
the strength of our website. And then
also just generally the the quantifiable
metrics that we'll use for that
particular keyword. Okay, so
this is critical. Okay? There is you
cannot do keyword research without
having a good template. So, you have to
have a template. You can take a lot of
what I've showed you here and you can of
build your own if you want, totally
doable.
Um or I just have these in Search OS.
Okay? So, I I put all my templates in
Search OS.
Uh and you can see here, you know, you
just open this up and this is on version
2.1.
Um and you can just go ahead and use
these templates and keep getting access
to them as we update them. All right, so
now that you know that you need to have
a proper keyword research template, the
next step is to actually go out there
and find keywords. The first technique
is to just use Google search data. So,
if you go into Google Ads and you go to
the Keyword Planner, you're going to see
directly from the source as far as
search volume. Okay? So, you click on
get search volume and forecast and we'll
just do a simple example for let's say
SEO to keep it really simple.
And we'll run this through and then
we're able to see
the exact search volume and even the
trend data related to that particular
keyword. Okay? Now, obviously, you're
going to want to expand this much more,
but just to put a seed in there. Now,
you can go to keyword ideas and we can
expand that keyword set a lot more.
Okay? So, when I do SEO, you know, add
that in there, we'll do SEO services,
we'll do AEO services, we'll do AI
search optimization,
and so on and so forth. You just keep
adding these seeds related to whatever
you're going after. Okay? Then we do get
results and then we're going to be able
to see a decent amount of keywords.
Okay? And so, this is really good for
just kind of like that high-level
analysis as far as the Google as far as
Google Ads go, as far as Google search
data goes.
But, it it it's missing a lot, okay? So,
it's going to give you demand data as
far as volume and trending, but it's not
going to give you a whole lot after
that, okay? Now, just to add some
clarifications on this, this competition
column, this is not SEO competition.
This is purely competition if you're
running Google Ads, okay? So, just want
to make that clarification there. This
is Do not use that as competition for
organic. That's purely for ads. But,
like I said, this is still really really
powerful just for, you know, getting a
quick look into keyword data. And
obviously, you don't have to invest in
any tools. You just come in here and you
you have Google Ads
give you that data, okay? So, that's the
first technique. The second technique is
another Google product is Google Search
Console. Once again, it's free to use.
You sign up. You can get your query
data. And you can get a lot of great
insights by doing this, okay? It's not
It's missing a lot, once again, because
like we look at this and we see, "Okay,
well, we look at these keywords."
And we can see kind of four metrics. We
can see clicks, impressions, CTR, and
position, okay? That's all great, but
once again, it's missing some critical
some critical competition data, okay?
You see this data and you're like,
"Okay, this is cool. It's got a lot of
demand, but it doesn't tell the whole
story of who you're up up against for
those keywords." And that's absolutely
critical, okay? But, this is good, once
again, for a high-level overview. It's
It has tons of useful data. So, very
quickly, you can use Google Ads and also
Google Search Console
to to really You could technically build
a whole keyword strategy doing that,
okay?
It's not going to be comprehensive, but
it it can get you in in a good place.
Let's just say that, okay? The next
technique you can use, you can actually
go directly into Google itself, okay?
So, we're going to go into Google
and let's just search something like
SEO. We'll keep it on the SEO topic. All
right, so we're going to go down here.
We search SEO and there's a couple ways
you can actually do this on Google. So,
you can actually go into here and just
start doing suggested um keywords. Okay,
so you just keep running different
queries like this and you can start
seeing the different keywords that are
popping up. These are all suggested
options. These are all keywords that you
could technically pursue. Okay, another
thing you could do is you come down here
and go to people also ask. Okay, you
could technically just copy all of
these, pop them into your uh keyword
database and you'll be good to go. Just
make sure you label them as people also
ask. Okay, and each time you expand
these, just keep doing this over and
over and there's plenty of extensions
that do this. But just manually, you can
do this and you can copy them just like
this and pop them into your keyword
template. Okay, another thing is for
some queries, you will see this things
to know, but usually only for queries
that have a lot of search demand. You'll
see this, but still some useful stuff
you could pull from here, right? Still,
you know, kind of blends a little bit,
you know, with people also ask, but you
might find some unique ideas in there as
well. So, the all of these ideas that
you find are what are going to be
defined as zero volume keywords. That
does not mean that they're bad keywords.
It just means they don't have
quantifiable demand and that is not a
problem because most keywords are
completely unknown to SEO tools, right?
Even Google itself doesn't know about
the large majority of keywords that even
exist. And this is only getting more
complicated over time because the length
of a query keeps expanding because of AI
platforms. Very much more conversational
queries. Okay, so the length of a query
is expanding, which means there's much
more complexity in these queries. So,
then you can do the same exact thing on
Replit. You just go into Replit and you
can search something like SEO
and you can either start to look at some
of these existing topics here and start
to add these to your database, or you
can actually go into the the subreddit
itself and start to see what are the
topics that are being talked about a lot
because a lot of these topics that pop
up in these subreddits don't typically
have search volume and any any volume
that they may get is always going to be
lagging and in the future. So, the
advantage here is that you're going to
find these ideas that people are talking
about right now, you're going to jump on
these topics, you're going to be able to
get some early momentum on these topics
and that can give you huge advantage
over your competitors. Now, on YouTube
we can do the same exact thing. We go to
SEO and we can do once again suggested
searches and see, okay? Honestly, most
of these are going to be very similar to
Google. So, you're not going to find
anything very different by doing this,
but it's actually much better just to go
into the actual channels that exist,
okay? So, we can look at any of these
channels here. We'll go into my buddy
here, Matt D'Avella, and what I would do
is I would go to his videos and I would
go by Well, first, you know, you can do
by popular, but I'd be I'd be careful by
doing popular because YouTube changes so
much. So, like for example, if you did
this exact topic that he did here that
was from 5 years ago that has insane
amount of views, you're not going to get
the same amount of views on your video
by targeting this topic, okay? Even this
one here about ChatGPT, which both he
and I attacked this, you know, this
topic as soon as ChatGPT came out,
you're not going to get the same amount
of views because there's the the
platform has been flooded by content
that's all about that topic now. So, you
have to be a first mover on these
topics. So, a better thing to do is go
to latest and then look at the latest
topics that have driven the most views.
And then the last technique I'll show
you for finding keywords is just to use
a tool like Rankability. So, this is
what I personally use. So, all these
things that I just showed you today,
this streamlines all of that into one
simple operation. So, within, you know,
3 to 5 minutes, you'll have done
everything I just showed you and you can
be completely done. That's and that's so
to me, you know, better use your time.
That's why I use it. Uh but I'll just
show you real quickly what this looks
like. So, this is for St. Louis SEO
consultant. So, we'll go ahead and just
run, you know, things like that are very
similar to what we do. St. Louis SEO
agency, same uh see here, St. Louis SEO
consultant.
And then we can say, you know, say we'll
do St. Louis um
uh we'll do St. Louis AI search
optimization
services. And then we'll do St. Louis
AEO services, okay? So, those are just
seeds, by the way. You just enter some
seeds. They don't have to be exact to
what, you know, what you think it is.
Don't try to you don't have to figure it
all out. But the more specific you are,
the better, okay? So, then what you can
do here is you can do by all sources,
which means it's going to go and and
look at all the different sources that
we talked about here plus more, which
I'll show you in a second. But if you
wanted to if you wanted to kind of uh
get the the tool to get more focused on
a particular group, you could do
trending, you could do Reddit, YouTube,
and even e-commerce, okay? So, actually
we'll extract topic ideas from Amazon,
Walmart, and eBay, okay? So, this just
these are different routes you can take.
But for this for the sake of this
example, I'm just going to go
uh with with all sources, okay?
Now, this is where things go to the next
level.
You can integrate your knowledge base,
okay? So, we'll go over here to advise,
and you'll see in the advise section
you can integrate a couple things.
Number one is you can integrate your
knowledge base artifacts, and you can
integrate data into this advisor. Now,
I'll show you in the context of
Rankability cuz I have way more
knowledge knowledge base artifacts in
here. But you can see here, these are
all the different knowledge base
artifacts, and these are directly from
the website, okay? So, what it will do
is when you do that keyword research,
it's actually going to go to that
content and extract first-party topic
ideas from that content, okay? So,
whatever you put in into your knowledge
base, this tool will use it to to
generate content ideas that your
competitors are absolutely ignoring nor
would even have access to, okay? That's
how valuable this is going to be. So,
you go ahead and click that on and then
also Google Search Console. This is
incredibly powerful. So, I just showed
you how you could do that yourself, but
this is a little more powerful because
you when you click this on,
instead of going into Google Search
Console like this and you've got like,
"Okay, where do I start? I've got all
this data. I've got 14 million
impressions and I got to dig through.
Like, where do I even begin?" Well, you
can certainly mess around with filters
and it's it's decent. Or you could just
use this tool which makes it way easier
because what happens is when you put
these seeds in,
uh it goes through in Google and and uh
Rankability will automatically filter
and only give you the keywords that are
directly related to the seeds that you
entered. So, you have to waste all your
time filtering through all the keywords
to try to find relevance, okay? So, once
that's all good, you just go ahead and
click start keyword research. Okay, so
that typically takes about 3 to 5
minutes to complete and you'll see why
because it's quite intense. So, I want
to show you a couple of things. First,
when you when you get your initial
report here, it's it it's simple by
design, but it's really when you start
to go into the filters where you really
start to see some good stuff, okay? So,
couple of key things to look at here.
Number one is obviously look at the
relevance of the topics. As I mentioned,
that we're really really focused on
relevance, okay? That is the key. We
want to try to get the most relevant
topics imaginable. But then, we also
have the source, okay? And I'll show you
all the different sources that this
pulls from, but we can see we got
Google, Google Search Console, and I'll
show you the other ones. We've got
automatic clustering. So, you can
certainly go and do this yourself. You
can even use ChatGPT to help you with
clustering, but this also just does it
automatically. And then we've got all
the standard data I talked about
earlier, okay? Now, let's open up the
filters. I'll show you a couple of
things. First, um you can sort this
obviously if you want to really quickly,
but we can also look by cluster, okay?
We can sort it by cluster, and then we
can also sort it by sources. So, like I
mentioned, first we can look at just
pure Google search data, okay? So, this
is the pure Google search data that uh
is coming directly from Google. This is
coming directly from Google, okay? Then
we go over here, we go to AI. Now, we're
doing this by doing a lot of advanced
stuff on the back end, but you can see a
lot of these topics are really, really
unique, okay? They're not all going to
be great cuz obviously it's AI, but it
gives you some kind of unique angles
that you probably wouldn't have even
thought of. We also pull from Reddit, as
I showed you earlier. So, instead of
having to dig through Reddit, this does
it automatically. We also have YouTube.
Instead of having to dig through
YouTube, you can just go ahead and see
the ideas right here. You can see we
pulled some ideas from the knowledge
base. This particular client did only
had one page in the knowledge base, but
the more comprehensive your knowledge
base is, the more ideas that this will
generate, okay?
And then trending topics, okay? Going
and finding unique ideas related to
these core topics. And then of course
the big one, which is Google Search
Console. And as you can see, there's
tons of ideas in Google Search Console
that you can go after, all right? So,
this is a way to really streamline your
keyword research efforts. And
ultimately, the goal here is to do
keyword research once and not have to
worry about it. And this brings me to
step number three, which is actually
prioritizing your keywords. So, now you
know how to find keywords. Showed you a
bunch of different tools you can use.
But now, what do you actually do to
determine what keywords to go after and
in what order? Okay, so now what you're
looking at is data that I extracted
directly from Rankability and then just
put it into our template. Now, we don't
necessarily always use this template.
Usually, just we'll control it all
within Rankability, but if you're, you
know, using any type of keyword research
technique, this is a good place to kind
of put all of your topics in here. And
so, you put this in, and there are a
couple things can happen when you create
a template like this.
Number one is automatic categorization
of intent. Once again,
this is done in Rankability, but if you
want to do kind of have a more manual
route, you can do that. We can also see
categorization by opportunity, okay? So,
we got the low-hanging fruits, and then
we've got the other opportunities uh
that also exist in here. So, like I
mentioned earlier, clustering
opportunities, we can see these, and
these are keywords that are just not
performing well, okay? So, good example
of this is looking through some of these
and saying like, are there any keywords
here that maybe we should create a
dedicated page for, okay? So, an example
would be like St. Louis digital
marketing. This is a good one cuz you
don't have any page on this website
about digital marketing services. So,
this would be a good one to splinter and
build a dedicated page for. And so, you
get the idea, right? And these are not
ranking well. So, that's a clustering.
Then we go over here, and we can start
to see how this data will start to uh
kind of come together, and this will
help you ultimately determine what
keyword you want to go after, okay? So,
when you look at this, as I mentioned,
not all of the data's in here. You got
to go and find target word count, you
need to find lowest DR. These are
kind of manual, you have to go through
and do these, okay? Uh and then also
relevance, you you can pull that
relevant score directly from
Rankability, but in general here, um you
can see how this starts to come
together. Even with not hitting all the
metrics, you can see we can even just
start to sort this, and we'll see what
keywords are getting good scores, okay?
So, we look over, St. Louis SEO company
is getting a good score because we're
ranking well for it, it has high CPC, uh
and that means it's a good target, okay?
And all of these make a lot of sense,
okay? The reason why it's missing on
some elements is the relevance, but we
can see even AI SEO agency, this is a
great keyword. We're not ranking well
for it, but it's incredibly valuable,
okay? And in the in the in the context
of St. Louis, we'd want to rank for best
AI SEO agency in St. Louis, okay? We
wouldn't care about going national for
that, we want to stay in whatever the
target market is. So, this is the
process you can go through to start to
filter through these keywords. Now, the
way that I've been doing it recently is
I just do this all inside of
Rankability. So, I find a keyword in
here like this and I say, "Okay, that
looks like a good keyword." So, then
I'll go over here, St. Louis SEO
services. Let's say I'll mark a few of
these that I want. St. Louis SEO
consultant, St. Louis AEO, and then
let's try to find maybe one more good
one here. Uh we'll just add these. Okay,
so we'll add these to our main list.
And then this is where the magic
happens. So, you can do this uh two
different ways. Okay, the first way is
you can click into a particular keyword.
This is where you start to go to the
next level, but you can also do this
manually, right? You take this keyword,
go in here in incognito window, and just
start analyzing uh what's showing up.
Now, when I'm doing an analysis for a
particular keyword, I'm looking at
what's showing up in the SERPs. Who am I
competing against? So, a couple key
things I'm looking at here. Number one
is
uh what are the SERP features that are
popping up? Well, we got a local pack,
okay? So, yes, traditional search result
above the local pack, but that's
extremely rare. Usually a local pack is
above the fold uh is usually the first
SERP feature. But, what that tells us is
we want to occupy two different spots
here. We want to rank want to rank in
the traditional, but we also want to
rank in the Google Business Profiles in
the local pack, okay? So, now we've
occupied two spots on the first page.
That's critical. But then we go down
here and we see, is there anything else
here that uh we we need to be thinking
about? Number one is Yelp is here, okay?
So, we go and look at Yelp and we see,
like, are we actually showing up in this
listing? Because this is critical for uh
AI search optimization, right? You can
do well in Google, but if you're not
showing up in these directories, you're
probably not going to do really well in
ChatGPT or Perplexity or the other
non-Google AI platforms. So, I would
look at it and say, "Okay, it looks like
we probably have a gap here. We probably
need to go and build a profile here,
okay?"
And then so on and so forth. I'm looking
through There's another one, Clutch,
another great example.
Uh are we showing up here? If the
answer's no, we go build a profile here,
we start working to build our profile
here, and that becomes an important part
of our work, okay? So, this is what
we're looking for. And so, all of those
things that I talked about today as far
as
uh the value of a keyword and uh the
competition and the organic CTR
potential, like that's all combined into
this one
uh KO score that we call it, okay? Now,
competition, this is what makes this
very unique. You If you've used any
tools in the past, you've probably seen
competition as KD or some sort of other
metric. Those metrics are fine, but the
the biggest problem with those metrics
is they're only measuring how many links
you need on the page level. And what
this is measuring is it's looking at the
competitors' overall domain strength,
and then also looking at how many links
you're going to need on the page level.
You need both of those combined together
to truly know how competitive a
particular SERP is, okay? So, you can
use this to ultimately guide you in your
keyword selection process, okay?
And then uh we There's some automatic AI
analysis on every keyword here.
And then in the SERPs, like all that
SERP analysis we just did, uh you can do
it live here, right? So, we've got We
can see Google Business Profiles, we can
see the traditional search results, and
this is just kind of a geeky thing, but
you can see even uh how keyword rich the
Google Businesses are, the Google
Business Profiles, and also how keyword
rich the rankings are, right?
Highlighting each individual keyword of
that query. So, you can see kind of, you
know, what you're up against, right?
It's very important. And then we can
also see the position history over time,
uh how this changes. But, go back over
here, and a couple kind of key elements
is we're going to continue to add to
this, but if you look on YouTube, you
can actually see who's popping up for
this query on YouTube as well. So, when
I look at this, if I really wanted to go
hard on, you know, St. Louis SEO
consultant, like I have a video here
that's ranking at the top that's 11
years old. So, I could easily dominate
YouTube for this keyword, right? Like it
would be like no work at all. And then
we see all the stuff that's popping up
is all old videos that are, you know, no
offense, outdated uh and would should be
easy to beat, okay? So, you want to be
thinking about this search everywhere
optimization strategy. Don't just think
about Google. Think about traditional
search, local pack, YouTube, and of
course, AI mode, which matters a lot,
right? We want to see just because we're
doing well in traditional does not
necessarily guarantee that we're going
to do well in AI mode, okay? And that
we've seen this time and time again,
okay? And you can even see here uh that,
you know, St. Louis SEO consultant,
which is ranking incredibly well in
traditional, isn't even being used as a
citation source or a source of retrieval
here, okay? So, once again, proving that
just doing good SEO does not necessarily
translate really well into into AI mode.
And I'll just show you an example. St.
Louis SEO consultant ranks really,
really well, okay? So, we'll go to like
local, you know, it's got a we built a
Google Business Profile just kind of
prove our point how powerful having
keyword-rich business names is and like
it's number seven, it has no reviews,
and it's a service area business.
It it just has no business being here,
no pun intended, but it's because that
keyword-rich nature, right? It's really,
really powerful. Um and then we go down
here, you can see how it's doing well in
the in the grids. And then we go up here
though and we look at the traditional
search, you see this this particular
keyword-rich domain, it ranks
basically on every search engine, right?
Crushes across all the search engines,
but we go to AI answers and it's doing
okay, right? It's got Perplexity, it's
got Grok, but it's missing a lot, right?
It doesn't have chat GPT, AI overuse,
Gemini AI mode, like it's missing a ton
of places.
Um and you know, obviously that's not
ideal, right? And but the reason I'm
showing you that is because just doing
well there, you know, doing well even in
citation, doing well in traditional
search doesn't necessarily guarantee
performance in the actual AI answer,
okay? And that's a topic for a different
time. But for now, that is how I go
about doing keyword research these days.
And you can like I mentioned, there's so
many tools out there you can use.
There's so many different ways to find
keywords. But the way that I've just
been able to make my life a lot easier
is just to use Rankability cuz it gets
the keyword research process done in a
couple of minutes and then I can spend
my time on what actually matters. Go to
my list and I can really dig into these
keywords and get a really good
understanding
um of what I'm up against, right?
Because at the end of the day, it's not
about being able to find keywords.
That's actually the easy part. The hard
part is knowing uh what keywords to pick
because if you pick the wrong keywords,
you could waste a lot of time, energy,
and money going after a keyword that's
just going to be junk, right? And what
you want to do is is be very deliberate
with that process. Uh and one thing that
might help is
think in terms of clusters, okay? So
when you pick a keyword, let's say in
this case I'm doing AEO services in St.
Louis,
I'm going to go after this core topic of
AEO or AEO services and I'm going to uh
build out many supporting assets around
this topic. I'm not just going to go
after this once and then move on to, you
know, St. Louis link building services,
right? I'm not going to I'm not going to
go that quickly. I'm going to go a mile
deep on this cluster and then once I
feel like I've exhausted that cluster to
the fullest extent, then I move on to
the next one, okay? This is a mistake I
see all the time. People bouncing from
one, you know, topic to the next without
fully covering that topic. You have to
absolutely cover it all the way. So,
this is actually a really good keyword
to to finish off here because you'll see
zero search volume, okay? But, if we
actually look, AEO services, all right?
And this is why localized keywords are
tricky. But, if we go in here and we
look at AEO services, we'll see 210
searches. Now, this is national
national, you know, volume. But, even
national volume isn't accurate. What you
really want to be looking at is this.
How much is this keyword topic or how
much is this service offering or idea
growing year over year, okay? Because
there's an obvious trend going on now,
right? It's It's slow, but it's
beginning to grow. So, you're not going
to find volume for a keyword like this
cuz it's so new. Doesn't mean people
aren't searching it, though. And that's
why when I see stuff like this, I get
really excited because I know when I
start to look at the search results,
this is why having that kind of
keyword-rich highlighting here is so
important. But, check this out. We look
up AEO services, okay? Check this out.
Not a single competitor, not even one,
is targeting this keyword right now. Not
a single one, right? So, right this
second, I could go and build an asset,
boom, get it published, start ranking,
start getting that leverage, start
getting those clicks, and then it
becomes really really hard for the
competitors to catch up because once
you've you've already started to rank,
you start to get all the positive
signals, which we know
helps you solidify rankings even better,
okay? So, this is why these zero-volume
keywords are so powerful. And And this
is why you know, you got to jump on
them. Jump on them fast, especially if
you're an agency. You got to start going
after these keywords. So, hope that
helps. If you like this video, as
always, please like it. I got a lot of a
lot of cool videos coming here very
soon. So,
So, anyway, subscribe to get first
access. Thank you so much for watching.